"Nakagawa Hirotaka"
I'm Nakagawa Hirotaka, and
I transferred here from Tokyo.
東京から転校してきた中川広孝だ　宜しくな
Nice to meet you.
Hmph! Tokyo scum!
ふん　東京もんが
Hirotaka?
広孝
Kuya? Kuya, is that you?!
空也
空也なのか
It was a fateful reunion.
それは運命の再会であった
Rika sees no problems.
問題ありませんね
Yeah. Okay, we're good.
Let's go to the next scene.
よし　オーケーだ
次のシーン行くぞ
Everybody ready?
準備はいいか
Okay here!
オーケー
お　重い
This is heavy.
The Moon Rises
in the Sky
Okay, lights... camera... action!
じゃあ　本番
よーい　アクション
You've got some nerve!
お前　生意気なんぞ
H-How dare you?
な　何だと
How dare you say "how dare you"?!
何だとは何だ
Cut!
カット
じゃあ　次は
Right, the next one is...
Yozora-sempai.
夜空先輩
The sun is setting.
もうかなり日が傾いています
Anything else we shoot now
won't match our other footage.
これ以上撮っても絵が繋がりませんよ
That's that, then.
仕方ない
Okay, we'll pick it up tomorrow!
Meet in the club room after school!
よし　続きは明日だ
放課後また部室に集合
We're running low on time, so don't be late!
もう時間がないから遅れるなよ
Okay...
はい
I can't hear you!
声が小さい
Okay!
はい
Be My Friend
Yeah, you played dumb
Be My Side
But I saw right through you
I'll walk another step toward your side
I bet I can even reach your hand
"Haganai NEXT"
It's more than I imagined... every
day's a roller coaster
I always barreled ahead with everything I had
Our time won't last forever, now will it?
Now is all we have, so let's make
sure we remember this moment
Be My Friend
Yeah, you played dumb
Be My Side
But I saw right through you
I'll walk another step toward your side
So I can take your hand
Be My Friend
Yeah, I'm always gazing at the sky
Be My Side
But I'm still drawn to it
One more time! I'll reach out
to you as many times as you need
I bet I can even reach that star
"Stray Cats Overheat"
No scenes with Kotaro today either, huh?
今日も小太郎の出番はなしか
It's kind of a shame...
ちょっと残念な気もするけど
But being part of the crew is more
fun than I thought, so I guess it's okay.
まっ　裏方ってもやってみると案外面白いから
いいか
Oh, those must be the
score rankings from finals.
期末試験の順位表か
Second-Year Exam Rankings
Kashiwazaki Sena
900点満点中895点
895 out of 900?! How does
anyone even get a score like that?
どうやったら取れるんだ　そんな点
Mikazuki Yozora
And Yozora's first in our class, too...
夜空は夜空で うちのクラスじゃ一番だし
- Grrrrrr... Grrrrrr...
- What's with that?
何だ
Wh-What's your problem?
何ですか　君は
Huh? Um, I...
えっと　俺は
Hey! You're Kashiwazaki Sena's boyfriend!
君は柏崎星奈の彼氏
Grrrrrr!
Kashiwazaki Sena... that
woman is definitely my enemy!
柏崎星奈　やっぱりあの女は自分の敵です
Er, so who are you?
えっと　そういうお前は誰なんだ
Y-You don't know who I am?!
自分を知らないですと
I suppose I should've expected an
associate of Kashiwazaki Sena's to be rude.
やっぱり柏崎星奈の関係者だけあって失礼ですね
Are you famous or something?
何か有名だったりするのか
I'm Yusa Aoi, Year 2, Class 3!
I'm the student council treasurer!
2年3組遊佐葵　生徒会会計です
I ranked #2 on these tests!
今回の試験では二位でした
Wow...
Kashiwazaki Sena
Yusa Aoi
3組　星奈と同じクラス
If she's Class 3, she's
in the same class as Sena.
So you're #2 in our whole grade
and a student council officer!
学年二位で生徒会の役員か
That's amazing.
すごいんだな
That condescending attitude
is extremely obnoxious!
その上から目線が非常に腹立たしいです
I've been Kashiwazaki Sena's
runner-up since last year!
どうせ自分は去年からずっと柏崎星奈の下ですよ
I don't know about last year, but
I still think you're doing really great.
去年のことは知らんけど
それでも十分立派だと思うぞ
She's just tough, that's all.
相手が悪いだけで
Well, I still want to win! At least
in test scores, if nothing else!
それでも勝ちたいのです
せめてテストの成績くらいは
Glamorous looks, outstanding
grades, great at all sports,
あのきらきらとした外見の上　成績優秀　スポーツ万能
その上　お金持ちのお嬢様
and she's a rich little princess!
I feel like I've heard this before.
どっかで聞いたような評価だな
I know for a fact that the world
calls those like Kashiwazaki Sena
自分は知っています
柏崎星奈のような人のことを世の中では
"people with real lives."
「リア充」と呼ぶのだと言うことを
She gets to have a real life
and a boyfriend on top of that?!
ただでさえ「リア充」なくせに彼氏までいるなんて
人生勝ち組過ぎるではありませんか
It's patently unfair!
Look, slow down. I'm not dating Sena!
だからちょっと待って
俺は星奈と付き合ってるわけじゃないぞ
You can't fool me. You use
her first name with no honorific...
ごまかしても無駄なのです
下の名前を呼び捨てするなんて特別な関係に決まっています
you've obviously got a special relationship.
All the boys in our class use "-sama" for her.
自分のクラスの男子達は柏崎星奈のことを皆「様」付けて呼びます
It's no use. She's just not listening.
駄目だ　こいつ聞く耳持ってない
Honestly... I'm fighting
like mad to surpass her,
まったく　自分が必死で追い抜こうと頑張ってるあいだ
and meanwhile she gets
herself a cool boyfriend like this?
柏崎星奈はこんな格好いい彼氏と
I'm jealous!
羨ましいです
Hey, when you say "cool,"
are you talking about me?!
あのさ　もしかして格好いいって
俺がか
What, do you see anybody else standing here?
ほかに誰がいるのですか
And any way you look at it, you're cool.
どう見ても君は格好いいのですが
There's that understated blond
hair you clearly take such pains to dye!
明らかに拘りをもって染めている渋い感じの金髪
And you wear your pants rolled
up, because you've got fashion!
ズボンのすそなんか曲げちゃっておしゃれさんです
I know for a fact that the
world calls cool guys like you
自分は知っています
君のような格好いい男子のことを世間では
"bad-boy chic," you know!
「ちょい悪系」と呼ぶのでしょう
N-Nobody's ever talked
about me like that before!
そんなふうに言われたのは初めてだぜ
Why are you making that funny face?!
何面白い顔をしているのですか
I can't believe you've got a sense
of humor on top of the cool factor!
格好いい上にユーモアまで備えているなんて
You're obviously the kind of awesome
boyfriend suited to Little Miss Perfect!
あの完璧すぎる柏崎星奈に相応しい素敵な彼氏ではないですか
I'm displeased yet jealous! Completely envious!
まったくもって不愉快もあり　羨ましくもあり　妬ましいです
I'm leaving.
自分はこれで失礼します
Yusa Aoi, huh?
遊佐葵か
I've met yet another weirdo...
また変わったやつと出会っちまったな
おーす
Yo!
Huh? You're all alone?
あれ　一人だけか
Yozora and Rika left. They said
something about location scouting.
夜空と理科はロケハンだとか言って出て行ったわよ
Apparently they want a shot
of the sun setting into the sea.
太陽は海に沈む絵がほしいんだって
Huh... Oh, I just remembered: I ran into
a girl named Yusa Aoi on my way here.
そうだ
ここに来る途中で遊佐葵ってやつに会ったんだけど
Who's Yusa?
遊佐って誰
What do you mean "who"?!
She's a girl in your class!
誰って　お前と同じクラスの女子だろう
Huh?
She's short, and she's got sort of reddish hair.
何か背が低くて　赤っぽい色の髪のやつ
Oh, yeah, that does sound kind of familiar.
確かそんなようなのもいた気がするわね
At least memorize the names of your classmates.
クラスメイトの名前くらい覚えとけよ
I memorized the girls who
sit next to me and behind me.
後ろと隣の席の女子の名前は覚えたわよ
Not that it paid off any.
覚えて損したけど
Did something happen?
何かあったのか
I've told you before: There are
only two types of girls in this world.
前に言ったでしょう
世の中には2種類の女子しかいないの
Yayoi
Yeah! Let's go together on Sunday!
- Great girls I hit it off with, and those other bitches.
- Yeah! Let's go together on Sunday!
あたしと仲良くしてくれる素敵な女の子と
Rui
I don't want to go there.
- Great girls I hit it off with, and those other bitches.
- I don't want to go there.
してくれないメス犬よ
Why should I have to remember
all those mongrels' names?
どうして駄犬の名前をこのあたしがいちいち覚えないといけないの
1.   Don't be like that. Come with us!!
2.   Should we go somewhere else, then?
3.   Fine, don't come! Moron!
Sena-sama
Fine, don't come! Moron!!
So she calls her classmates "mongrels"...
クラスメイトを駄犬呼ばわりか
Well, evidently this Yusa girl's name
一応その遊佐ってやつ
has been right below yours
on every single test ranking.
試験の順位発表でずっとお前の下に名前があるらしいんだけど
Why would I care about
other people's rankings?
知らないわよ　他人の順位なんて
Where are they even posted, anyway?
ていうか　それってどこで発表されてるのよ
On the bulletin board, obviously!
掲示板に張り出されてるだろう
Oh, huh.
そうだっけ
You've never looked?
見たことないのかよ
I can tell my rank from the paper that
has our percentiles and stuff, you know.
だって　自分の順位の偏差値とか書いてある紙でわかるじゃない
The only important
thing is that I come in first.
大事なのはあたしが一番ってことだけよ
You're really something.
お前すげえわ
Am I?
そう
What kind of studying do you
usually do? Do you have a tutor?
お前普段どんな勉強してるんだ
家庭教師とかか
I don't study except for going
to class and doing my homework.
勉強なんて授業と宿題しかやってないわよ
For real?! What about for tests, then?
マジすか　じゃ試験勉強は
That time with you was my only time.
この前やったのが最初で最後ね
That was kind of fun!
あれはちょっと楽しかったわ
Y-Yeah... I guess it was.
そうだな
So, Kodaka.
それで小鷹
Did something happen with that Yusa girl?
その遊佐とか言うのがどうかしたの
Eh, never mind.
もういや
Okay.
あっ　そう
こいつ　本当に興味あること以外にはとことん興味がないんだな
She really doesn't care at all
about stuff she's not interested in...
And yet when she likes something,
そのくせ気にいたものに対しては周囲がドン引きする勢いでずっぱしゅう
she gets so into it she makes
everybody else uncomfortable.
When it comes to Yozora, even if she
doesn't like it she gets practically criminal...
気にいたものじゃなくても夜空に対しては犯罪滑々
Actually, I guess the sneak
photo thing really is criminal.
いや　盗撮とか完全に犯罪か
She lives however she pleases
and does whatever she wants.
どこまでも自由奔放勝手気まま
And she's got the huge talent and
family circumstances to get away with it.
そんな生き方が出来てしまうだけの
ぶっちぎりの能力や境遇を備えた　生まれながらのお姫様
She's a born princess.
Maybe it's only natural for
the other girls to hate her.
ほかの女子が敵愾心を抱くのも無理ないかもな
Now that I think about it,
getting to hang out with her so casually
そんなやつとこんなふうに気楽に付き合えるってのは
might actually be an honor.
案外光栄のことなのかな
We found the perfect location!
最高のロケションが見つかりました
We're going straight out
to film it. Let's go, Meat.
すぐに撮影だ
行くぞ　肉
Hey...
ちょ…　まだ　セーブしてなかったのに
- I hadn't saved yet!
- You get ready too, Kodaka.
小鷹もすぐに用意しろ
Okay, okay.
はい はい
Shooting time!
The Moon Rises
in the Sky
And... action!
よーい　アクション
Grit your teeth, Hirotaka.
広孝　歯を食いしばれ
く　空也
K-Kuya...
Cut!
カット
Okay, we're good!
はい　オーケーです
Hey, are you sure this is okay?
おいおい　本当に大丈夫なのか
What do you mean?
何がですか
- How was it?
- The background is obviously a park.
背景　思いっきり公園だぞ
- Not bad.
- The background is obviously a park.
No need to worry!
心配御無用です
Rika will turn it into a perfect beach later with CG.
あとはCGで見事な砂浜に仕上げて見せますから
Look forward to it!
乞うご期待
じゃあ理科は編集作業があるので　これで
Well, Rika needs to go
edit this, so she'll see you later.
See you.
I know what she said, but can she
really manage it? She's no CG expert...
とか言ってたけど　何とかなるものなのか
CGだって万能じゃなかろうに
Why, if it isn't Kodaka-kun!
小鷹君ではないか
理事長
President?!
Fancy meeting you here.
奇遇だな
どうも　こんにちは
Hello, Sir.
Hi.
This school festival atmosphere
is quite pleasant, isn't it?
いいものだな　この学園祭の空気というものは
Yes, I suppose so.
そうですね
Your club is doing a
movie, if I recall correctly.
確か君達は映画を撮っているんだったな
Yes, Sir.
はい
Movies are nice. Hayato used
to drag me to them all the time...
映画はいいものだ
私も昔　よく隼人のやつに連れられて
President?
理事長
Oh, never mind.
いや　なんでもない
Now, what's this movie like?
それより　君達はどんな映画を撮っているのかね
Sena never told you?
星奈から聞いてないんですか
I don't have many chances
to speak with her, you see.
あれとはあまり話す機会がなくてな
I see...
そうなんですか
I'd love to see it when it's finished.
完成したら是非見せてもらいたいものだ
I feel a little shy about
having someone I know watch it.
知り合いに見られるのはちょっと恥ずかしいですね
By the way, Kodaka-kun...
時に　小鷹君
Yes?
はい
How is your relationship
with Sena coming along?
星奈との交際のほうも順調かね
Er, um...
えっと　あの
Perhaps you're embarrassed
to talk about it with me!
やはりこういう話をするのは気恥ずかしいかね
No, it's not that I'm embarrassed, it's
just... what do you mean, "relationship"?
いや　気恥ずかしいって言うか
交際って　何の事ですか
Oh, you don't need to play dumb about it.
何も惚ける必要はないだろう
Um... No, really, what?
えっと　いや　本当に何の事です
You and Sena are dating, aren't you?
君と星奈は交際しているのだろう
No, we aren't.
してないですけど
What?!
あーれー
Something urgent has come up.
I'll see you another day, Kodaka-kun.
急用が出来た
それでは小鷹君　また後日
Right...
Oh, no!
What's going on?!
どういうことだ
He's a funny guy...
面白いな　あのおじさん
Yo!
おーす
Kodaka, come with me.
小鷹　ちょっと来なさい
Hey!
Where are you going, Meat?
どこへ行くのだ　肉
We have to do something. We'll be right back.
ちょっと用事　すぐ戻るから
Hey, Sena!
おい　星奈
It's so hot...
あつー
Well? What did you want to talk about?
で　何の話だ
何か　あたしとあんた　パパに付き合ってると思われてたみたい
It sounds like Daddy
thought you and I were dating.
Oh, that.
やっぱりその話か
He said that to me
yesterday, too. It surprised me.
俺も昨日理事長にそんなこと言われて驚いたよ
Why did he think that?
どうしてそんな話になってるんだ
Well, um... How do I put this?
いや　そのう　なんと言いますか
D-Don't glare at me like that.
そ　そんな睨まないでよ
I'm not trying to glare at you.
睨んでるつもりはないんだが
Er, you remember how we all
went to the amusement park?
えっと　前に皆で遊園地に行ったじゃない
Y-Yeah, I do.
ああ　行ったな
あの時のチケット　パパからもらったんだけど
I got those tickets from Daddy...
And?
それで
The thing is, when he
gave them to me, I said...
その時あたしね　言っちゃったのよ
Yay! Now I can have
Kobato-chan for my little sister!
これで小鳩ちゃんを妹にできるわ
Pardon?
はい
D-Daddy got the wrong idea from that.
それで　パパが勘違いしちゃったのよ
意味わかんねえぞ
I don't get what you're talking about!
もう　察しがわるいわね
Sheesh, you're so dense! If you and
I got... m-m-m-married or something...
あんたとあたしが
そのう　け　け　け　結婚とかしたら
あたしの妹ってことになるでしょうが
Obviously she'd be my sister, right?!
結婚
Married?! I mean, yeah, but...
それはそうなるが
あの時はテンション上がっちゃって
At the time I was so excited,
I didn't think too deeply about it...
深く考えなかったんだけど
But now I remember him saying lots of stuff...
そういえばパパ　いろいろ言ってたのよね
Like "Are there plans for
Kobato-kun to become your sister?"
小鳩君がお前の妹になる予定があるのかっとか
and "How is your relationship
progressing?" and stuff.
仲は順調に進展しているのかっとかって
And what did you answer?
で　お前はそれになんて答えたんだ
"Don't you worry!
I've totally got this!" I said.
「ばっちりよ　任しといて」っで
Hey!
Aha, it turns out he meant my
relationship with you, not Kobato-chan!
いや　あれって
小鳩ちゃんとの仲じゃなくて
あんたとの仲って意味だったのね
お前なあS
Look, you...
I am deeply ashamed of myself.
面目しだいも御座いませぬ
Well, at least you've explained
things to him now, right?
でもまあ　理事長にちゃんと説明したんだよな
Yeah.
Okay. As long as he gets that it
was all a misunderstanding, it's fine.
そっか
ちゃんと勘違いだってわかってもらえたんなら
もういいわ
I feel kind of bad for the President,
but I'm glad it's all straightened out.
理事長にはちょっと申し訳ないけど
誤解が解けてよかった
So, here's what I wanted to talk to you about...
それで　ここからが本題なんだけどね
What? There's more?!
まだなんかあるのか
Uh-huh. And just so you
know, this part is not my fault!
言っとくけど　これはあたしかなんかやらかしたわけじゃないからね
It's something I only just now found
out, because of this whole mess...
今回のことが切っ掛けで　あたしも初めてしたことなんだけど
O-Okay.
You and I...
あたしとあんた
...are apparently engaged.
婚約してるみたい
Are you okay, Kodaka?
大丈夫　小鷹
Huh? Y-Yeah.
なんかね　あたしとあんたがまだ物心付く前に
Daddy says that back when
we were too young to remember,
あたしのパパとあんたのパパが約束したんだって
he and your daddy made a promise.
Basically, we're what you'd call "betrothed."
つまりいいなずけってやつね
いいなずけ
Betrothed?! This is like
something out of a soap opera...
そんなドラマみたいな設定が
何か誓約書みたいなのもあって
They even wrote up a pact,
and it has our thumbprints on it.
あたしたちの拇印も押してあったわ
They took it that far?
そんなものまで
Our prints were really tiny. It was pretty cute.
なんかね　すごい小さな指紋で　可愛かったわ
Oh, really? I don't remember this at all...
そうか　まったく覚えてない
I don't either! But look.
あたしだって　覚えてないわよ
でも　ほら
これって
This is...
It looks like you and I met a long time ago.
あたしとあんた　ずっと昔に会ったことあるみたい
For real?
マジでか
It feels kind of weird, you know?
何か変な感じね
Yeah, totally...
そうだな
Well, setting that aside!
まあ　それはともかくだ
Mm-hmm.
About the marriage thing...
結婚の話だけど
Mm-hmm?
An engagement we didn't make
ourselves isn't anything to worry about, right?
俺達の意志と無関係に決められた婚約なんて
気にすることないだろう
Y-Yes, you're right!
そ　そうよね
This is just something our
dads are randomly saying!
こんなの　パパ達が勝手に言ってるだけなんだもんね
Well, I dunno about "our"...
I doubt my dad remembers the pact.
ああいや　「達」って言うか
俺の親父のほうは多分この約束覚えてないと思う
Oh?
そうなの
So, no need for us to sweat this!
つうわけで　この件は気にする必要なしだ
R-Right! We won't sweat it!
そ　そうよね
気にしない　気にしない
ちょっとだけ惜しい気もするけど
Though it almost seems like a pity...
Nothing!
なんでもないわ
Even if we're not engaged, I'll make
Kobato-chan my sister all by myself!
あんたとの婚約なんてなくても
自分の力で小鳩ちゃんを妹にして見せるんだから
I don't suppose I can
get you to give up on that?
それはいい加減諦めてくれませんかね
Okay, let's go back to the club room.
そんじゃ　部室に戻ろうぜ
あたし達はいいんだけど
We may be fine, but...
I'm a little worried about
what that moron will think.
あの馬鹿がどう思うかだけ　ちょっと気になるかな
It's not like we have to tell
her, right? It's irrelevant anyway.
別に言う必要ないだろう
関係ないことだし
Well, maybe so...
そっかな
Yeah, you're right.
そうだよね
You're late! What were you doing?!
遅い
何をやっていたのだ
ちょっと野暮用よ
Nothing too important. Now, shall we go film?
さあ　早く撮影に行きましょう
All right, fine.
まあいい　では行くぞ
Let's go. Today we're starting
with the baseball field scene.
今日はグランドのシーンからだ
Time for more movie-making!
今日も映画やるぞ
Maria.
マリア
It's Big Brother! I'm gonna
make a movie with Big Brother!
お兄ちゃんだ
今日もお兄ちゃんと一緒に映画撮るぞ
Movie!
Come to think of it, I feel
like I'm forgetting something...
そういえば なんか忘れてるような気が
But you've got Sena-san,
so I guess that's out...
まあ　星奈さんがいるからしょうがないか
When Kate said "that's out," did she mean?
ケイトが言ってたしょうがないってのは　もしかして
そうだ
Oh, right!
Are you and Sena really getting
married? The hag said so yesterday!
昨日婆に聞いたんだけどな
お兄ちゃんは星奈と結婚するって本当なのか
婚約者って言うのか
The word is "fiancée," right?
Wow, you're so grown up if
you've got a fiancée, Big Brother!
婚約者がいるので
やっぱりお兄ちゃんは大人なのです　凄いな
So grown up! Way grown up!
大人　大人だな
ど　どういうことだ
What is she talking about?
Betrothed... And the two
of them met a long time ago...
いいなずけ
しかも二人は昔会っていたか
But hey, it's totally
irrelevant to us now! Right?
まあ　今の俺達には何の関係もない話だ
そうだろう
そうね　そのとおりよ
Right! That's exactly right!
Say, Rika-san.
なあ　理科さんよ
Yes, Yozora-san?
何ですかの　夜空さんよ
Which relationship is closer,
childhood friends or betrotheds?
幼なじみといいなずけって　どっちのほうが関係が深いかな
Rika believes most
people would say betrotheds.
一般的に考えていいなずけだと思いますよ
That's what I thought.
ですよね
Especially since they met as children.
しかも昔会っていたらしいですからね
One could say they're
childhood friends, couldn't one?
幼なじみであるとも言えますね
ですよね
That's what I thought.
Oh, please!
もう　鬱陶しいわね
We're saying it doesn't matter, so
what are you losing confidence for, idiot?!
当のあたし達がどうでもいい話だって言ってんのに
なんでそんなにうじうじしてんのよ　馬鹿
M-Meat...
に　肉
For Pete's sake! Come on, let's go film!
ああ もう　はら　さっさと撮影行くわよ
Sena-sempai is right, you know.
まあ　星奈先輩の言うとおりですよ
There's no use worrying about the
past and promises parents made, is there?
昔のこととか　親が決めた約束とか
そんなの気にしては仕方ないじゃないですか
Let's focus on the future, shall we?
前を向いていきましょう
Where are we filming today?
今日はどこで取るのだ
何かもう　どうでもいいや
Whatever. I don't care anymore.
B-Big Brother!
お　お兄ちゃん
What is it, Kotaro?
どうした　小太郎
広兄が　広兄が大変だんだ
It's Hiro-nii! He's in trouble!
何
What?!
Okay, cut.
はい　カット
How was it?
どうだった
Well...
Her mind is somewhere else, huh.
上の空だな
Shall we move on to the next scene?
次のシーンに行きましょうか
Man, I'm tired...
疲れた
Hiya, Big Brother.
やー　お兄ちゃん
Look, you!
お前なあ
Today was a train wreck thanks to you!
お前のせいで今日大変だったんだぞ
- Pardon?
- Wait!
はい
待って
Ah, I'm sorry about that.
それはすまなかったね
But you know, it's not like we're the only ones
でもお兄ちゃんと星奈さんが婚約してることを知ってるのは
who know you and Sena-san are engaged.
別に私達だけじゃないよ
Huh?
天馬さん　ことあることに喋ってるからね
Pegasus-san talks about
it every chance he gets.
I'd bet almost all of the sisters
and faculty here know about it,
学園のシスターや教員はほとんど全員知ってるだろうし
and there might even be students who know.
生徒の中にも知ってる子はいるかもね
Ugh, that guy's got a big mouth!
あのおじさん　口軽いな
He was probably really happy.
よっぽと嬉しかったんだろうね
そっか
Huh, so that was just
Pegasus jumping to conclusions...
あれが天馬さんの早とちりだったんだね
Hmm? What did you say?
何だって
何でもないよ
Oh, nothing!
So, I hear you guys are making a movie?
ところでお兄ちゃん達　映画を撮ってるんだって
Yeah.
What's it about?
どんな内容なんだい
I couldn't make heads or
tails of Maria's explanation.
マリアの話じゃ　どうも要領を得なくてね
Yeah, I believe that.
だろうな
Ah, so it's a coming-of-age story
centered around a transfer student.
なるほど
転校生を中心にした青春ものか
何だか　「坂道の上の太陽」みたいな話だね
That reminds me of Boys Over the Slope.
Boys Over the Slope?
「坂道の上の太陽」
Yeah. It's a Japanese
coming-of-age movie, a cult classic.
うん　知る人ぞ知る和製青春映画の名作でね
I like it a lot.
私もかなり好きなんだ
お兄ちゃんもぜひ見てみるといいよ
You should check it out, Big Brother.
Huh, maybe I will! It could
be good reference material.
参考になるかもしれないし　見てみるか
お　お兄ちゃん
B-Big Brother!
どうした　広太郎
What is it, Kotaro?
It's Taka-nii! He's in trouble!
孝兄が　孝兄が大変なんだ
What?!
何
The Moon Rises in the Sky
By: Mikazuki Yozora
Draft 3
I can't believe you, Yozora... Your script...
夜空
お前
お前の脚本
...is totally cribbed from this!
ぱっくりじゃねえか
光ったはずの星
A stray cloud blocks my view
迷った雲が邪魔して
Of the star I know should be shining there
見えなくなる
What should I believe in?
何を信じたらいい
I was on my way to breaking
不安定すぎる世界で
The treasure bred in this all too changeable world
育った宝物壊しかけてた
Because I was afraid of losing it
なくすのが怖くて
不条理だって
Those days of sighing "This is absurd"
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
And flailing inside my birdcage
We were gazing up at the same sky
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
君の手を握った時
When I gripped your hand,
you gripped back, didn't you?
握り返してくれたね
These joined hands are stronger than any wings
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
We can fly higher even without wings
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
So I know we'll be okay trying now
きっと今なら大丈夫
大空輝く星を掴もう
Let's grab the stars twinkling in the sky
I-I shall tell you exactly what happened.
あ　ありのまま起こったことを話すぞ
私は星奈と小鷹が交際していると思っていたんだが
I thought Sena and Kodaka-kun
were dating, but it wasn't true.
実はそんなことはなかった
な　何を言ってるのかわからないと思うが
You may not understand what
I'm saying, but I don't really get this either.
俺もどういうことなのかわからない
Now, now, calm down.
まあまあ　落ち付いてくださいな
You seem happy, Kate-kun.
何だか嬉しそうだな　ケイト君
いや　そんなことないですよ
Oh, no, not at all!
そ　そうか
R-Really?
"The Sad-Case King and
the Stone-Cold Story"
次回　「残念王と笑えない話」
Next time: "The Sad-Case
King and the Stone-Cold Story."
前途多難だね　お兄ちゃんも
Big Brother's got a rough life, huh?
こりゃ私にもワンチャンあるかな
Maybe I have a chance now?